RYAN MACEACHERN

Software Developer



CONTACT

C

778.587.3982

 $\succ\!\!\!<$

ryan.maceachern.tech@gmail.com

in

LinkedIn.com/in/Rmaceac

9

Victoria, BC, Canada

SKILLS

Languages

JavaScript

Ruby

HTML

CSS

Python

Typescript

SQL

Frameworks/Libraries

NodeJS

Three.js

React

EJS

Rails

FRB

jQuery

Bootstrap

Ajax

SASS

Express.js

Testing

Storybook

Jest

Cypress

Mocha

Chai

Capybara

Rspec

Systems & Databases

Git + GitHub

PostgreSQL

Firebase

GraphQL

Audio + Visual

Blender

Photoshop

Lightroom

Da Vinci Resolve

Reaper

Other Software

Quickbooks

Xero

Figma

HubDoc

SUMMARY

Full-Stack Developer with a background in adventure tourism and finance. I am excited to use my extensive experience in customer service to understand users' challenges and desires in the apps that I develop. I love working in collaborative teams that prioritize educational functions of apps and accessibility of information.

EDUCATION

WEB DEVELOPMENT DIPLOMA

Lighthouse Labs

April 2022

ADVENTURE GUIDE DIPLOMA

Thompson Rivers University

2012 - 2014

WORK EXPERIENCE

OWNER/OPERATOR

Blue Sky Bookkeeping - Self-Employed | 2017 - Present

- Working with clients from a dozen different industries to translate what matters most to them and ensure their values are prioritized in the communication and organization of their business finance.
- Built a financially stable business from scratch through self-education, resourcefulness and a constant desire to learn.
- Recently saved a client over \$7,000 in PST charges using my attention to detail to make amendments to their sales tax filings.

HR LEAD & OPERATIONS COORDINATOR

Maple Leaf Adventures | 2019 - 2020

- Filled multiple, extremely dynamic roles that required regular, thoughtful communication with a crew of 50+ employees, ship's crew, engineers and many other employees/clients, each with a different set of values and priorities.
- Solved countless logistical and interpersonal conflicts while ensuring a seamless and unforgettable experience for our guests.
- Spearheaded the company's training sponsorship program in conjunction with WorkBC's Employer Training Grant, processing employee applications and writing grants for a variety of programs. This allowed for many of our crew and employees to gain essential industry training and advance their careers for free, or simply a fraction of the cost.

LEAD KAYAK GUIDE

One Ocean Expeditions | 2018 - 2019

- Led groups of ~15 guests with a small team of assistant guides through remote locations on the Antarctic Peninsula while managing safety, logistical and customer experience operations on board the expedition ship.
- Regularly made consequential judgement calls that prioritized the safety of my team and guests, while also providing an incredible experience for our clients.